backbase.com 2019-07-11

# Privacy Policy - Backbase

**This Privacy Policy explains how we process the personal data that we collect from you when you use our websites, apps, platforms and services governed by this Privacy Policy (our “Services”).**

## 1\. When this Privacy Policy applies

The following Services are subject to this Privacy Policy:

  * Use of the Backbase.com website
  * Requesting a white paper, demo or other information
  * Registering for the [Backbase Blog](http://www.backbase.com/resources/blog) or receipt of Backbase emails
  * Registering for Backbase events
  * Any other Backbase Services this Privacy Policy is attached to

Please note that we also have specific Privacy Policies for

– Academy: the use and ordering of (online) trainings and the use of the [Academy website](https://www.backbase.com/services-partners/backbase-academy/) –[ Academy Privacy Policy](https://www.backbase.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/privacy.pdf);

– Recruitment: your job application via our [Online Recruitment System](https://careers.backbase.com/) – [ Recruitment Privacy Policy](https://www.backbase.com/privacy-policy-online-recruitment/);

– [Backbase Community](https://community.backbase.com/privacy) – [Community Privacy Policy](https://community.backbase.com/privacy).

## 2\. Information we collect

We collect your personal data when you sign up and/or when use our Services:

  * Upon signing up: you will be asked for several personal details that are necessary to create your account and offer you our Services. These fields are marked as compulsory. Additional personal details may voluntarily be provided by you, which will enable us to provide full-featured Services and a higher degree of customization.
  * When you use our Services, either if you previously signed up for them or not: we will collect and process personal data regarding your use of such Services to improve your overall experience. You may limit the amount of information we collect by setting your privacy preferences in our Services, modifying the settings of your device or browser, or through the way you use our Services.

### **2.1 Personal Information**

**2.1.1 Personal Details**

This is information you give us which personally identifies you, such as your name, email address, telephone number, date of birth or home address. Your personal details will be processed for the following purposes:

  * To verify your identity and assist with the identification of users:  
_– Your email address provides one way in which we can verify your identity and make it easier for you to get back into your details if you ever forget your password._
  * To send important notices:  
_– We will send you communications about changes to our terms, conditions, and policies._
  * To improve your user experience and the overall quality of our Services:  
_– Knowing your basic personal details lets us personalize any communications we send to you. You may go the Preference Center and choose which content you would like to receive._

### **2.2 Information about your activities**

**2.2.1 Browsing Behavior, Device Information and Interactions**

This entails the tracking of your actions (repeated site visits, interactions, keywords, online content production, etc.) when you access and use our Services and the building of profiles over time. It also includes information about the devices and methods you use to interact with Backbase Services and content.

We capture information about your Operating System and Internet Browser when you visit a Backbase website or use our Services, including information that is automatically logged when you use our Services (e.g. requested information, timestamp, IP address).

We will process your behavioral, device and interactions information for the following purposes:

  * To provide, maintain, protect and improve products and Services, and to develop new ones:  
_– For example, information about how you browse our websites or search for products can be used for data analysis and research, to deliver better user journeys, provide more relevant search results or structure the way the information is shown in our Services._  
_– When you install a Backbase mobile app, a unique application number along with information about your device is sent to Backbase, making it easier for Backbase to maintain its apps and Services and offer automatic updates._
  * To improve your user experience and the overall quality of our Services:  
_– Your activity such as the pages you visit or the items you view teaches us what you find important and most interesting to you on our Services so that we can tailor your experience around what matters to you most and display personalized content._  
_– Device and platform identifiers let us know which device you are using to access our Services in order to customize and optimize them to your device and improve your overall user experience (e.g., providing more relevant content and advertising on the device or browser you are using)._  
_– Storing data locally on your device allows us to improve things like website performance and loading of content even when you are offline._
  * To provide you with more useful information, more relevant content and offers, and latest news about products and events:  
_–For example, following a link to a tutorial from a marketing email, or following Backbase on Facebook or Twitter._  
_– Understanding how and where you interact with Backbase means we can provide you with more personalized and helpful information through your preferred communication channels._
  * To protect our users and Backbase:  
_– We can monitor unusual or suspicious activities on our Services, such as automated abuse, so that we can address it quickly and inform you about potentially fraudulent activities affecting your account._  
_– We might also use your personal information for internal auditing, in order to comply with applicable legal requirements._

**2.2.2 Location Information**

We gather your location data, including real-time geographic location, where you have expressly authorized us in accordance with your privacy settings in the Preference Center, installed apps, browsers and devices. We use Location Information for the following purposes:

  * To improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services:  
_– We can use any geographic information contained within your photos to help you catalogue your images by location._
  * To provide you with more useful information, more relevant content and offers, and latest news about products and events:  
_– We can serve you with content which is relevant to your current location._
  * To verify your identity and assist with the identification of users:  
_– For example, Backbase verifies your IP address in some territories during the sign-up process to ensure that you are willing to sign up for our Services and to mitigate the risks of identity theft._
  * We do not use your location information to track your private activity for purposes other than those set in this section.
  * We do not share location information with third parties other than Backbase group companies nor sell it to anyone.

### **2.3 Information we receive from third parties**

When you use social login, we retrieve basic profile information from your chosen social identity provider for the following purposes:

  * To verify your identity and assist with the identification of users:  
_– If you sign up to our services using a social media site, we receive basic profile information like your name, age range and country of residence._
  * To provide, maintain, protect and improve products and Services, and to develop new ones:  
_– We may use social network identifiers if you are automatically syncing content from that site, such as adding photos to online photo storage services from Facebook._

### **2.4 Settings and Preferences**

Certain Backbase Services allow you to specify your personal preferences (e.g. preferred language). Users may also specify their privacy preferences with regards to things like receiving marketing communications.

  * We use this information to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services:  
_– Knowing your country and language allows us to display our Services in your local language, time zone and regional formats._

### **2.5 Purchase Information**

This comprises information about services you buy through Backbase Services, for the following purposes:

  * To provide, maintain, protect and improve products and services, and to develop new ones:  
_– We use your purchase information in order to complete and fulfill any orders you place through the Backbase Services._  
_– We customize our Services according to your purchase history._
  * To send important notices, such as software release notifications and communications about purchases or changes to our terms, conditions, and policies:  
_– We use your purchase information to ensure we send you an accurate order confirmation email._

### **2.6 Cookies and other technologies**

Cookies and similar technologies (e.g. web beacons) are small pieces of information used to store technical and/or personal details, identify users of a service and enable certain functionalities. Backbase also makes use of third party cookies.

## 3\. How we share your information

Backbase (defined in “Definition of Backbase” at the bottom) is the data controller, that is, the entity determining the purposes and means of the processing of the personal data collected from you.

The personal data processed when you use our Services will not be transferred without your prior explicit consent, to other individuals or businesses, for their own use, other than Backbase group companies. Some vendors or other entities with whom we have a business relationship to provide products, services including Backbase group companies will however have access to and process your personal information, but only on behalf of Backbase and only to supply services to Backbase related to the purposes set in this Privacy Policy.

Your personal data are transferred by and between Backbase and other Backbase group companies for the same purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Backbase is a global organization that has affiliates, business processes, management structures, and technical systems that cross national borders. Therefore, Backbase may use resources and servers located in various countries across the globe. Accordingly, your personal data may be transferred outside the country where you use a Backbase website or service or otherwise provide Backbase with your personal data. In case you are an EU citizen, this may include countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) that do not have laws that provide specific protection for personal data. In such case we will make sure other additional legal measures are in place following applicable law.

Backbase is committed to protecting your privacy. Your personal data is held on secure servers and is not processed for any purposes other than those set out in this Privacy Policy. The servers Backbase uses to store this information are accessible to authorized staff only and Backbase ensures that adequate security measures are in place.

## 4\. Marketing communications

If you provided your consent when signing up to our Services, or at a later stage, Backbase and/or other Backbase group companies will use your personal information for marketing purposes and to inform you about other products and services, which Backbase thinks might be of interest for you. You can specify whether you wish to receive such information by ticking the appropriate box in your registration form. You will be able to opt out from receiving such information at any time by editing your emailing preferences of your account or by unsubscribing using a link provided in all applicable communications.

## 5\. How to exercise your rights

You have the right to access, correct, update or delete your data as well as any other right applicable in your jurisdiction by accessing the Preference Center, clicking on the link provided in our communication emails, or accessing the relevant section of the Backbase websites or apps.

In order to delete your data, you need to access the Preference Center on the Backbase [website](https://www.backbase.com/preferences-center/) and delete your account. Note that after the deletion of your personal data, it cannot be recovered and any data and content stored on the Services will also be permanently deleted. We will also delete your personal data once it is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was originally collected.

Backbase will need to hold your personal information locked where required by applicable laws and during the relevant statutes of limitations, even if you ask for its deletion. This term should typically not exceed 5 years in most jurisdictions. Backbase will not delete your personal data where it refers to an active relationship or a product or service explicitly requested by you (e.g. a recent purchase made at a Backbase Services).

## 6\. Your commitments

By signing in to any of our services and accepting this Privacy Policy, you confirm that you are above the age applicable in your jurisdiction for engaging in contracts. You also confirm that you have previously gathered any necessary parental/guardian consent required in your country of residence, where applicable. We will contact you at any time in order to check the above and reserve the right to suspend or delete your Backbase ID accounts in case you cannot prove this.

You guarantee the quality of the information provided in our Services. All personal data you send to Backbase must be real, accurate and kept up to date. You take full responsibility that your information is accurate, updated and that it complies with this principle. You also guarantee that you have gathered the explicit consent from anyone holding any personal image, intellectual property or other rights over your content, authorizing you to upload and store it in our Services.

By signing up for any of our Services, ticking the appropriate box or clicking the appropriate button when you access any Backbase Services, even if they require no registration but through which your personal information is collected –, you authorize Backbase and other Backbase group companies to use such data for the purposes described in the registration and in this Privacy Policy. You expressly agree to the processing of your personal data in the terms set in this Privacy Policy and its transfer to the Backbase group companies specified in section 3.

## 7\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will update our Privacy Policy from time to time to ensure you are promptly informed of Backbase’s data processing activities. We will not engage in any processing operations that might put in risk your personal information, and will gather your explicit consent where necessary to safeguard your right to privacy. We will keep you updated on any changes to this Privacy Policy through the Services. We will also use any of the communication methods provided by you to inform you on important changes to this Privacy Policy. If you continue using our Services after having been unequivocally informed on the updated Privacy Policy, you agree to be bound by the updated terms.

## 8\. Contacting Backbase

Please contact Backbase with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy from following Backbase global website: <https://www.backbase.com/about/contact/>

Also, you can contact Backbase’s marketing affiliates specified below according to your place of residence:

In the Privacy Policy, “Backbase” shall mean Backbase BV and “Backbase BV’s marketing affiliates” specified below providing services in your country or region.

USA and Canada: Backbase USA Inc., 10 10th Street, Suite 325, Atlanta, Georgia 30309, United States of America.

Asia: Backbase Asia-Pacific Pte. Ltd., 16 Raffles Quay, #33-03 Hong Leong Building 049581 Singapore.

Rest of the World: Backbase Europe BV, Jacob Bontiusplaats 9, Unit 504, 1018 LL, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.
